# SALEEM KASSAB

Software Developer Damascus, Syria 00963 0959 270 763 <u>saleemkassab5@gmail.com</u> LinkedIn Portfolio



## **SUMMARY**

Diligent software developer working on a variety of implementation projects from start to finish in a top telecommunication firm. Very detail-oriented in problem-solving using business and technical approaches. Committed to improving business productivity and efficiency. Specialized in applying technical expertise to develop insightful solutions applicable to current business practices.

#### **SKILLS**

- ASP.NET
- Oracle SQL/PLSQL
- Data Engineering

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Software Developer

Syriatel Mobile Telecom, Syria | Apr 2022 - Present

Syriatel has been leading the Syrian mobile telecommunication market since 2000 with 4926+ telecom locations, including 3G and LTE technology, 20+ million customers, and 5000+ employees. Visit website

- Providing the executive board with the needed daily studies (daily revenue, Power solutions...) to support their decisions in improving the network performance by 100%.
- Coaching and motivating the team members to reach optimum performance and successfully contribute to achieving Corporate, Department, and Unit Objectives.
- Developing and maintaining of 4+ Technical Performance Decision Support Systems, in addition to supervising the process of data modeling in order to create a suitable pool of OLAP systems.
- Designing Source to destination Mapping and developing suitable automated ETL (Extract-Transform-Load)
   Processes.
- Encapsulating data into web services in order to feed third-party applications, and implement efficient code.

# **Applications Management Specialist**

Syriatel Mobile Telecom, Syria | Sept 2017 - Mar 2022

- Manage the production environment, and implement the needed configurations for 10+ systems related to Marketing, Corporate VIP, and Customer Services departments.
- Handle technical issues and prepare maintenance plans.
- Monitor systems performance using professional technologies.

#### Call Center Representative

Syriatel Mobile Telecom, Syria | Aug 2016 - Aug 2017

Help 100+ customers daily by responding to inquiries, demonstrating and explaining products, services, and
offers in order to persuade customers to purchase products or utilize services.

## **EDUCATION**

## Master's Degree, Web Technologies

Syrian Virtual University, Syria | 2021 - Present

## Bachelor's Degree, Information Systems and Data Networks

Syrian Virtual University, Syria | 2016 - 2020

# Diploma of Education, Network Engineering

Damascus University, Syria | 2012 - 2016

# **PROJECTS**

#### Radio Performance Platform

Syriatel Mobile Telecom Back-end Developer

Business intelligence platform that integrates with Huawei MAE system for technical performance measurements with Datawarehouse. Multi-tenancy system which supports multiple stakeholders and subjects for Radio, Transmission, and Core decision-makers to build their daily studies and share them with the executive board.

## Integrated Bulk Messaging System

Syriatel Mobile Telecom Back-end Developer

Platform to send a bulk message for a segment of mobile numbers for Syriatel Customers.

## Revenue Sharing System

Syriatel Mobile Telecom Back-end Developer

Helps Marketing and Sales team to follow up revenue which is coming when companies use Syriatel Services

#### **HONORS & AWARDS**

Great Job Card, Syriatel Mobile Telecom | Mar 2023

Awarded due to speeding up the warehouse report's generation methods +100 times

#### Great Job Card, Syriatel Mobile Telecom | Nov 2022

Awarded due to the first voluntary task I did to speed up the work in general by 60% where I completely rebuilt the
used ETL mechanism professionally. In addition to build a new (logging, SMS alarming, and daily reporting) tools
to track and provide the management and team with the ETL process' daily status.

Employee of the Month, Syriatel Mobile Telecom | May 2017

Achieving the highest rate of selling services among team members in the shortest time.

#### **LANGUAGES**

- Arabic: mother tongue
- English: professional working proficiency